When you start up a terminal, what do you see?
当启动一个终端时 你会看到什么？
Usually, you see a Shell prompt.
通常你会看到一个 Shell 提示符
But what it says will differ from system to system.
但不同的系统 它的内容会有所不同
Like, the one that comes with Git Bash for Windows
例如 用于 Windows 的带 Git Bash 的
will look like this.
是这个样子
But the one over on the Mac will look like that.
但 Mac 上的是这个样子
Here, this one shows the name of the computer I'm using,
在这里 这个显示的是我正在使用的计算机的名称
which is flexo, the current working directory, which
即 flexo 及当前工作目录
is the home directory, abbreviated tilde, and the name
为主目录 后加波浪号 以及我用于
of the user I'm logged in as, which is student.
登录的用户名 即 student
But there's a whole bunch of information
但是你可以在 Shell 提示符中
that you can put in the Shell prompt.
放入一大堆信息
This here is from the Bash manual, which unfortunately
这里的这个来自 Bash 手册 但是不幸的是
doesn't get installed in Git Bash for Windows,
它并未安装到用于 Windows 的 Git Bash 中
but you can look it up online.
但是你可以上网查找
In order to use any of these or many other codes
为了使用你可以放在其中的任何或
that you can put in there, you put them
很多其他代码 你需要将它们
in the PS1 Shell variable.
放在 PS1 Shell 变量中
And where would you do that?
但是你在哪里这样做呢？
Well, in your .bash profile, usually--
通常是在 .bash_profile 中
or .bashrc if you're on Linux, or if you did that trick to get
或如果你运行的是 Linux 系统 在 .bashrc 中 或者你通过一些技巧
it to run there as well.
来让它在那里运行
So here's a .bash profile containing a complicated PS1
这是一个包含复杂 PS1 提示符的
prompt.
.bash_profile
Let's see what that does.
来看看它能做什么
Oh wow, now this prompt is almost as colorful as the one
哇哦 这个提示符和 Windows 上的一样
over on Windows.
色彩丰富
And it has a little clock in it, which is pretty handy.
而且还带时间 非常方便
So what do people put in PS1?
那么 人们都往 PS1 中放什么信息呢？
Well, a lot of developers have a display information
大多数开发人员会让它显示
about the current state of the project they're working on.
他们正在从事的项目的当前状态
You'll see more about that in a later course.
你会在后面的课程中看到更多
Me, I usually keep it pretty simple.
我通常会使它保持简单
This complicated one, I actually came up
对于这个复杂的部分 我实际上
with using a site called bashrcgenerator.com.
使用一个叫做 bashrcgenerator.com 的网站
Especially when I'm building courses
特别是我在构建课程时
and I don't want to distract you with what directory I'm in,
我不想分散你的注意力寻找我在哪个目录中
sometimes I'll just set PS1 to a single dollar
有时候我直接将 PS1 设为一个
sign followed by a space.
美元符号后跟空格
I'm going to keep it simple.
总之简单就好